Guide to the Lovelace Marionette Theatre Company Records, 1952-1984 CTC.1986.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Lovelace Marionette Theatre Company Records
1952-1984
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Lovelace Marionette Theatre Company
CTC.1986.01
14 Linear Feet (21 boxes)
The Lovelace Marionette Theatre Company was created by Margo Lovelace in 1949. This collection contains the records of the award winning Pittsburgh area puppet theatre company. Included are photographs, performance films, scripts, newspaper clippings, business files, and sound recordings.
Acquisition Information
Gift of The Pittsburgh Children's Museum and Mrs. Margo Lovelace Visser, 1986.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Biography
The Lovelace Marionette Theatre Company (also known as Rikes's Puppets, Lazarus Puppets and Margo's Moppets) was formed in 1949 by Margo Lovelace Visser as a traveling forum for her interest in puppet theatre. In 1964 a permanent home for the company was established--the first such permanent home for a puppet theatre company in the United States. Located at 5888.5 Ellsworth Avenue in Pittsburgh's Shadyside neighborhood, this professional puppet theater specialized in performing their own adaptations of classic and folk tales as well as their own original stories for both children and adults. They also pioneered the experimental theatre programs of Jean Cocteau, Jean Giraudoux and Moliere using rod puppets and Japanese-style bunraku figures. Having outgrown its facilities on Ellsworth Avenue, in 1977 they shifted the stage to the Carnegie Museum of Art Theater offering a full subscription season of puppet theater. The Theatre collaborated with New York-based Mabou Mines--training their actors on the use of bunraku figures; Pittsburgh's Ironclad Agreement Theatre Co.--on the American Premiere of Gov't Owned Apples; and the Pittsburgh Public Theatre--in a 1978 production of Balyasnikov. Other noteworthy performances have included a 3-week residency at the Smithsonian Institute; selection by Theatre Association of Pennsylvania (1977 - 1981) for an annual showcase of Pennsylvania's finest professional theatre; at the Union Internationale de la Marionette Festival Mondial in France and the Three Rivers Arts Festivals.
Among its other activities, the Lovelace Marionette Theatre Company also provided training and apprentice programs for young people, including the noted American theatre director, Peter Sellars. They developed a cultural enrichment program in 1970 for Pittsburgh Public Schools eventually expanding to 145 schools in Western Pennsylvania. Instruction has played a major role in its activities. The company developed a residency program in which students spend time in workshops learning about all aspects of puppet theater in a direct hands-on approach. Also offered were workshops for teachers to learn puppetry skills for integration into the classroom. The regular staff of LMT Co. has included David Visser, Heather Mathieson and Pamela Zarra. The creative driving force behind this venture has been its founder Margo Lovelace Visser. She studied at Carnegie Institute of Technology (now Carnegie Mellon University), and with Cedric Head's Kingsland Marionettes, the German puppeteer--Erhard Reis, and Moscow's Central Puppet Theatre (Lovelace Puppets have been on displayed in the museum from 1966-1981) at the request of Sergei Obraztsov. She has also traveled widely exploring puppet theaters around the world and collecting masks and puppets. Her collection is presently on deposit with the Children's Museum of Pittsburgh. Ms. Lovelace was an active member of the American Marionettes Council, the Union Internationale de la Marionette, a member of committees for both Pennsylvania Council on the Arts and the National Endowment for the Arts. She produced a short subject film in 1978, Museum Piece, which was nominated for an Academy Award by the Academy of Motion Picture Arts and Sciences. Other awards include a bronze medal from the Union Internationale de la Marionette, a finalist in the American Film Festival and a Golden Eagle Award for another Film, The Puppet Proposition. In 1981 she was awarded the Theodore A. Hazlett Governor's Award for Excellence in the Theatre Arts.
During the last years of the Lovelace Marionette Theatre Company an umbrella organization, The Marionette Theatre Arts Council, was formed to administer the Lovelace Theatre programs as well as providing educational opportunities and cultural enrichment through the medium of puppet theatre. Among the most noteworthy endeavors was the sponsorship of performances of the Drak Puppet Theater of Czechoslovakia and Das Puppenspiel Theatre of Germany. The organization ended operations in 1983.
Previous Citation
Lovelace Marionette Theatre Company Records, 1952-1984, CTC.1986.01, Curtis Theatre Collection, Special Collections Department, University of Pittsburgh
Lovelace Marionette Theatre Records, 1952-1984, CTC.18, Curtis Theatre Collection, Special Collections Department, University of Pittsburgh
Arrangement
The collection is organized into seven series:
Series I. General Operation Files, 1950-1985
Series II. Newspaper Clippings and Press Releases, 1955-1985
Series III. Diaries, 1952-1983
Series IV. Scripts
Series V. Photographs and Artwork
Series VI. Audio Recordings, 1967-1972
Series VII. Video Recordings, 1956-1970
Scope and Content Notes
The Lovelace Marionette Theatre Company Records are arranged into seven series. The first four series are all paper based and make up the bulk of the collection. The Photographs and Artwork Series is divided into four subseries - Photographs, Negatives, Slides, and Artwork. Series VI-VII are audio recordings and video recordings, most of which are on obsolete formats.
Videotapes; Puppet theater -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Puppet theater companies -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Theater -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Puppets; Rod puppets; Bunraku puppets; Marionettes; Clippings (Information artifacts); Diaries; Scripts (Documents); Photographs; Audiotapes; Video recordings (physical artifacts); Theater; Obrazt︠s︡ov, S. V. (Sergeĭ Vladimirovich); Pennsylvania Council on the Arts; Three Rivers Arts Festival (Pittsburgh, Pa.); Lovelace, Margo; Pittsburgh Children's Museum; Lovelace Marionette Theatre Company; Iron Clad Agreement (Theatrical company)
- General Operation Files, 1950-1985; I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  These files contain the office files, correspondence, minutes, account books, etc. for the operation and organization of the career of Margo Lovelace. The files are in chronological order. Box five contains oversized materials that are out of order due to their large format.
  - Address book (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Art and Lore of Puppets - manuscript (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Awards (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Cartoons (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Contracts (Box 1, Folder 5-6)
  - Correspondence, 1950-1985 (Box 1, Folder 7-10)
  - Correspondence - undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Drak: Czechoslovakian Puppet Theater (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Financial account books, 1965-1970 (Box 1, Folder 13-16)
  - Financial account books - undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Financial account book, 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Financial account book, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Financial - miscellaneous materials (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Gov't Owned Apples (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Greeting cards (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Head, Cedric (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Heinz Endowment (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - History - Lovelace Marionettes (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Idea for a Puppet Theater at a Summer Colony - manuscript (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Insurance (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Japan - Letters and programs (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Lazarus puppets (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - McMillan, W.G. (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Mailing Lists (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Manual of simple puppetry (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Margo on Margo (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Marionette Theatre Arts Council - Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Marionette Theatre Arts Council - Board minutes (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Marionette Theatre Arts Council - By-laws (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Marionette Theatre Arts Council - Positively Puppets (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Marionette Theatre Arts Council - Positively puppets (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Marionette Theatre Arts Council - Promotional material (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Marionette Theatre Arts Council - Report (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Membership cards (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Music for the puppet show (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Notebook (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Notebooks (Box 3, Folder 1-4)
  - Notes - miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Notes for lecture on Children's Response (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Obratsov, Sergei (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Passport - Margo Lovelace (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Pennsylvania Council of the Arts (Box 3, Folder 9-10)
  - Practical Puppets by Everyone - manuscript (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Program - Architruc (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Program - Aria da Capo (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Program - Balyashnikov at the Pittsburgh Public Theatre, 1977-1978 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Program - Beauty and the Beast at the Carnegie Museum of Art, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Program - Drak, June 1980 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Program - Fire Boy (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Program - Four and One (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Program - Fourth grade assembly (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Program - Jack and the Beanstalk, 1979-1980 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Program - Happy Birthday at the Pittsburgh Playhouse, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Program - Love's the Best Doctor at the Carnegie Museum of Art, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Program - The Magical Kingdom, 1981-1982 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Program - Punch and Judy at the Grandview Theatre (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Program - Ragtime and All That Jazz at the Carnegie Museum of Art, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Program - The Reluctant Dragon (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Program - Top Notch Hopscotch (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Program - Winnie the Pooh at the Carnegie Museum of Art, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Promotional materials, 1965-1982 (Box 4, Folder 18-19)
  - Proposal for Carnegie Institute (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Puppet Workshop - Handouts (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Puppet Workshop - Promotional material, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Puppet Workshop - Scheduling notebook, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Puppeteers of America, 1980-1983 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Resume - Margo Lovelace (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Sarg, Tony (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Sherlock (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Smithsonian Institution, 1978-1980 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Union International de la Marionette - Newspaper clippings, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Union International de la Marionette - Correspondence, 1966-1972 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Union International de la Marionette - Receipts (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Villa Maria College, 1977-1978 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Architruc - Poster (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Daily News Ad Proof (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Plan of set-up puppet stage area (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Puppets: Past and Present - Poster (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Puppet clothing patterns (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Newspaper Clippings and Press Releases, 1955-1985; II.
  Contained in this series are newspaper clippings, magazine articles, etc. relating to the productions of the Lovelace Marionette Theatre Company and its general activities. Also included are press releases used by the company. All files in this series are in chronological order.
  - Newspaper clippings - undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1955-1985 (Box 6, Folder 2-22)
  - Press releases, 1976-1983 (Box 6, Folder 23-24)
- Diaries, 1952-1983; III.
  These are the daily diaries and appointment books kept by Margo Lovelace Visser. Although incomplete they offer a general guide to the daily activities of the Mrs. Visser and her theater company. The diaries are in chronological order.
  - Diaries, 1952-1964 (Box 7, Volume 1-12)
  - Diaries, 1965-1972 (Box 8, Volume 13-23)
  - Diaries, 1973-1979 (Box 9, Volume 24-33)
  - Diaries, 1980-1983 (Box 9, Volume 34-38)
- Scripts, IV.
  Included in this series are adaptations of classic, folk, and contemporary plays as well as the Lovelace Company's original works. The vast majority of the scripts are undated. These materials are arranged in alphabetical order by title.
  - Aladdin (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Alice in Wonderland (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Alice in Wonderland: Tweedledum and Tweedledee (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Anansi (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Architruc (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Beauty and the Beast (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Bicentennial Show (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Brave Little Tailor (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Carnival in Rio (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Carnival of the Seventh Moon (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Christmas Carol (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Christopher Columbus (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Cinderella (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Commedia Circus Varieties (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Crackerjack Clowns (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Divine Comedy - Original Translation (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Days of the Great Buffalo (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Easter Basket (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Emperor's New Clothes (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Emperor's Nightingale (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Gov't Owned Apples (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Hansel and Gretel (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Huck Finn and Tom Sawyer (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - The Humbles of Hogback Hill (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Incredible Holiday Machine (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Jack and the Beanstalk (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Little Prince (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Little Red Ridinghood (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Little Scarface (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Love's the Best Doctor (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Lucis Toyshop (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Momotaro (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - The Musicians of Bremen (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Naropa (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - The Nativity (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Peter Pan (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Pinoccio (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Princess and the Pea (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Puss in Boots (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - The Quacks (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Ragtime and All That Jazz (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Rapunzel (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - The Reluctant Dragon (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Rumpelstiltskin (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Sleeping Beauty (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - The Story of Joseph (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Three Billy Goats Gruff (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - The Three Wishes (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Upset the Fruitbasket (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Tsar Trajan (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Top Notch - Hopscotch (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Toby and the Adult (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Winnie the Pooh (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Wizard of Oz (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Scripts - Unidentified (Box 11, Folder 27)
- Photographs and Artwork, V.
  The Photographs and Artwork series is divided into 4 subseries - photographs, negatives, slides, and artwork. Within each subseries, the files are arranged in alphabetical order.
  - Photographs, 1.
    - Aladdin (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Alice in Wonderland (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Apollo of Bellac (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Aria di Capo (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Audiences (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Audience - Carnegie Institute Museum of Art Theatre (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Baker, Danny (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Beauty and the Beast (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Behind the Scenes (Box 12, Folder 9-10)
    - Behind the Scenes - Afternoon Conference (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Behind the Scenes - George pulls some strings (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Behind the Scenes - Norman graduates (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Behind the Scenes - Sunny Builds a Mountain (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Brave Little Tailor (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Bunraku (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Carnival in Rio (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Coat of Many Colors (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Christmas if for Children - NBC New York City, 1956 (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Christmas Carol (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Christopher Columbus (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Days of the Great Buffalo (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Drak - Czechoslovakian Puppet Theatre (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - Emperor's New Clothes (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - Faust, Johnny (Box 12, Folder 25)
    - Gov't Owned Apples (Box 12, Folder 26)
    - Grand Turk (Box 12, Folder 27)
    - Guignol (Box 12, Folder 28)
    - Hammock Room (Box 12, Folder 29)
    - Hansel and Gretel (Box 12, Folder 30)
    - Huck Finn and Tom Sawyer (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Incredible Holiday Machine (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Ironclad Agreement (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Jack and the Beanstalk (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Keystone Cop (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Kingsland Marionette Collection (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Kingsland Marionette Summer Camp (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Lazarus Puppet Theatre (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Lincoln Elementary School Students (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Little Red Ridinghood (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - London Puppet exhibit, April 1979 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Love's the Best Doctor (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Lovelace family (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Lovelace, Margo (Box 13, Folder 14-15)
    - Lovelace Marionette Theatre - The 'Cave' (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Lovelace Marionette Theatre - Exterior (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Lovelace Marionette Theatre - Interior (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Lovelace Marionette Theatre - The workroom (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - 'Mad' workshop for the Masses (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Mathieson, Heather (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - McMillan, W.G. (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - Ozanam Puppets (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - Performances - Miscellaneous (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - Performances - On tour (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - Performances - Point State Park, 1958 (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - Peter and the Wolf (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - Peter Pan (Box 13, Folder 28)
    - Pierrot (Box 13, Folder 29)
    - Puppets (Box 14, Folder 1-3)
    - Puppets - Shadow (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Pictures at an Exhibition - Das Puppenspiel (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - The Puppet Proposition (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - The Puppet Proposition - Penn State, 1978 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Puppet Workshop - Erie (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Ragtime and All That Jazz (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - The Reluctant Dragon (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Rike's Puppet Theatre (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Rumpelstiltskin (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Scrub Brushes (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Smithsonian Institute - with Senator John Heinz (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Soviet Union (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Tales Told Round the Fire - Tzar Trajan (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Teacher Workshop - Pittsburgh, 1978 (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Toby (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Trick Skeleton (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - Wedding on the Eiffel Tower (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Wizard (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - Unidentified (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Negatives, 2.
    - Aladdin - School show (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Alice in Wonderland (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Audiences (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Beauty and the Beast (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Behind the Scenes (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Bunraku (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Drak (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Ellsworth Avenue (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Gov't Owned Apples (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Incredible Holiday Machine (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Jack and the Beanstalk (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Keystone Cop (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Love's the Best Doctor (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Lovelace Home/Workshop (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Lovelace, Margo (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - McMillan, W. G. (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Munich collection (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Performances (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - Performances - Point State Park, 1959 (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - Performances - Three Rivers Arts Festival, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - Pierrot (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - The Puppet Proposition (Box 15, Folder 22)
    - Puppets (Box 15, Folder 23)
    - Das Puppenspiel - A Christmas Carol (Box 15, Folder 24)
    - Ragtime and All that Jazz (Box 15, Folder 25)
    - Ragtime and All that Jazz - Mime (Box 15, Folder 26)
    - Ragtime and All That Jazz - Scrub Brush (Box 15, Folder 27)
    - Ragtime and All That Jazz - Tap Dancer (Box 15, Folder 28)
    - Ragtime and All That Jazz - 'Lollipop' (also Keystone Cop) (Box 15, Folder 29)
    - Tales Told Round The Fire - Tzar Trajan (Box 15, Folder 30)
    - Tales Told Round The Fire - Little Scar Face (Box 15, Folder 31)
    - Toby (Box 15, Folder 32)
    - Visser, David (Box 15, Folder 33)
    - Unidentified (Box 15, Folder 34)
  - Slides, 3.
    - Beauty and the Beast (Box 15, Folder 35)
    - Carnival in Rio (Box 15, Folder 36)
    - Emporer's New Clothes (Box 15, Folder 37)
    - Jack and the Beanstalk - David Visser's Hawaii production (Box 15, Folder 38)
    - The Little Prince (Box 15, Folder 39)
    - Punch and Judy - Hartwood Acres, 1976 (Box 15, Folder 40)
    - Scenery - Miscelaneous (Box 15, Folder 41)
    - U.S.S.R., 1976 (Box 15, Folder 42)
    - Unidentified (Box 15, Folder 43)
  - Artwork, 4.
    - Betsinda (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Bicentennial Show Costume Plates (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Children (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Clowns (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Commedia della Arte (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Costuming notes (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Dancers (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Fairy Blackstick (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - House (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - How puppets pick up - Chinese (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - King Julio (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Man with Beret (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Molly - Days of the Great Buffalo (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - More of Winnie the Pooh (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Mrs. Gruffanuff (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Naropa (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - Noh Masks (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - Notebook (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - Pinoccio, Fox, and Fish (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - Prince Bulbo (Box 16, Folder 20)
    - Puppets - Miscellaneous (Box 16, Folder 21)
    - Sets - Miscellaneous (Box 16, Folder 22)
    - Rumpelstiltskin (Box 16, Folder 23)
    - Wedding on the Eiffel Tower (Box 16, Folder 24)
- Video Recordings, 1956-1970; VII.
  The video recordings in this series are in alphabetical order by title of producition. There are three subseries - 16 MM, 8 MM, and videotape. The videotape cassettes in this series are Umatic format, which can be viewed on the ground floor of the Hillman Library.
  - 16mm, 1.
    - The Little Prince - Outdoor performance (Box 16, Reel 1)
    - Princess Snowflake and Her Friends - American Inventory, 1956 (Box 16, Reel 2)
    - Promotional Film - Miscelaneous footage of performances, etc. (Box 21, Reel 3-5)
    - Puss in Boots (Box 21, Reel 6)
    - Space Place (Box 21, Reel 7-8)
    - Three Billy Goats Gruff (Box 21, Reel 9)
    - Three Billy Goats Gruff - School (Box 21, Reel 10-12)
  - 8mm, 2.
    - Balyashnikov - Pittsburgh Public Theatre (Box 21, Reel 13)
    - Bicenntennial Show - Frick Park (Box 21, Reel 14-17)
    - Jack and the Beanstalk - Carnegie Museum of Art (Box 21, Reel 18)
    - Ragtime and All That Jazz - Extra footage (Box 21, Reel 19-24)
    - Tales Told Round the Fire (Box 21, Reel 25-26)
    - Unidentified (Box 21, Reel 27)
  - Videotape, 3.
    - Christopher Columbus, May 6, 1969 (Box 21, Reel 1)
    - Christopher Columbus, May 9, 1969 (Box 21, Reel 2)
    - Lovelace Marionettes, May 1, 1970 (Box 21, Reel 3)
    - Unidentified - Two-inch videotape (Box 21, Reel 4)
    - Children's Public Service Announcements (Box 21, Cassette 1)
    - The Days of the Great Buffalo - Commercial, 1982 (Box 21, Cassette 2)
    - Magic of The Lovelace Theatre (Box 21, Cassette 3)
- Audio Recordings, 1967-1972; VI.
  The audio recordings in this series are in alphabetical order by title of production. All the materials in this series are reel to reel audio tape, with the exception of the last item - an interivew with Margo Lovelace. This interview is on audio cassettes.
  - Alice in Blunderland (Box 17, Reel 1)
  - Apollo of Bellac (Box 17, Reel 2)
  - Apollo of Bellac - Live performance, May 12, 1972 (Box 17, Reel 3)
  - Beauty and the Beast, 1971 (Box 17, Reel 4)
  - Before Divertisement (Box 17, Reel 5)
  - Brave Little Tailor, January 5, 1972 (Box 17, Reel 6)